hello I'm live in came up I was sitting
here trying to plan in my head a bit of
what I'm gonna say like a topic to write
into the top and there was something
that was like no you're not supposed to
just go just go do whatever it comes out
for 10 minutes
even if it's crap specially that's crap
yeah um yeah the more I need to listen
to that so ridiculous but I was just
sitting here thinking about how just
like the real limitations that I have
where like I can't Society very much
demands and puts on a pedestal activity
and being productive and action
improving all of all of these things and
although part of me still has some of
those things like I still want to
improve in certain areas and where I
truly want to improve I just like allow
the improvement to happen as opposed to
forcing it and I it happens everywhere
though which is the point like it
doesn't really happen based on my focus
but mostly it just happens by beautiful
coincidence it's like okay I need to
learn this lesson this lesson in this
lesson and where I don't learn though
the universe just repeats them again and
again and again pretty good okay and
some of them are hard to learn like some
of them I even know what they are but I
can repeat them continually and then
other ones
I repeat because I can't figure out what
it is I can't figure out what is causing
it and one of my lessons I don't know if
it's a lesson for everyone else but but
for me is acceptance because the truth
is we don't know what anyone else's
lessons are the only you're living life
from inside one being and the entire
world is tainted by that and made
beautiful by that it's bad like weird
sometimes
a lot of the time and that's okay it's
the language that comes out but it is
tainted by it like it's like that is
what how you perceive the world and so
you think everyone else is kind of
similar to you has your level of
intelligence and experience and I do it
we do it by default but they don't
they're living their own life they're
doing to a large degree the best they
can
we're all doing the best we can even
when we're not doing the best we can
it's because that's the best we can like
it's like well if only I'd loved above
above and I could yeah but you're not
doing that so it's the best you can
like we're gone we take for granted that
certain things are easy we look out and
see that they're easy for other people
and think they should be easy for us and
then maybe they're not and we judge
ourselves or things that are super easy
for us we like having a problem with it
for we need to have compassion that you
only know this one viewpoint so all
these other viewpoints we can figure out
together what we have in common because
the truth is we have a ton in common but
nothing that you have is in common with
everyone and nothing come whatever I was
so focused my whole life on obtaining
knowledge and becoming smarter and
smarter and smarter to be able to solve
solve problems and learn more and learn
more learn more and only when that was
taken away from me in a large part only
when obtaining more knowledge became
rather impossible at least it the way
that I had been and his society says to
do it which is like like learning this
thing
force yourself to learn this thing and
so you read this stuff and you jam it in
your head and whatever way you can and
you try to memorize it and I like almost
starting from remember what it was like
for me before
when I was able to do those things when
I didn't ever have to learn how to
memorize because what like then no no
that's not true at all
there were times I definitely memorized
things like word definitions and and
such they were usually memorized for a
very specific short period of time to
write a test and I was never the
greatest at jabbing information I had
but most information stuck in a way that
made it awesome and my brain still makes
new connections will still do that but I
cannot force it to do that the more I
force it to do that the less it works
and that has been the biggest blessing
because it means that I was forced to
not continually learn new things I had
to sit with what I already knew and
figure out solutions for myself from
that space because I'm a problem solver
and I like to solve problems given the
information I don't have the desire the
ability or the I feel like that's enough
the desire or the ability to do the
actions to put into place the problem
solving but I'm fairly good at
problem-solving so I can give good
advice to other people not so much type
it myself but I got sidetracked by my
neighbors and whatever happens with me
living in the city is with other people
as it becomes like Suns are always there
are sounds contribute me and can be
physically painful and so and definitely
anxiety painful
they definitely cause it whatever you
taking out intelligence which is the
whole point I'm allowed to get on can
gyms allow it's let my brain flow and do
what it wants to do because it's its
best self then it saved the world like I
just have to be able to communicate it
which is the irony because I can't do it
I can't force it I can't I just have to
allow it and so taking the next step but
the universe has in place is what I'm
doing this Friday after postponing for
four months it's like okay
message received this seems like it has
nothing to do with the save the world
project he me communicating it but I
again that it was my next step on the
GPS and everything stalls until it's
like when I mean by that because I act
like you know everything that I've ever
said which of course you know um the
University acts like or the gone or
whatever works for you works on GPS
system and I'm very much a planner I
want to see everything out before me and
yet the truth is when you like you only
actually get the next step at least in
your personal life it's like okay the
next thing the next thing I still want
to plan out the entire and to fix them
we're all been in a way and it's like
not that not like everything has to go
for you in a plan a genie people to
understand the bigger picture before we
can start taking action in my opinion
because people want to tweak things that
change everything there are some like
it's like okay we'll just do the work
called first phone though I'm a
problem-solver not a doer of the work
but I'm willing to do what work I need
to do but I have real-world limitations
I mean that I can't do that work and
I've meant to limitations that mean that
I can't do that word and that means I
have to work in community and figure out
how to work in community and figure out
how to communicate this enough and let
it be imperfect in the world and learn
it just drawing the right people who
could be like hey this is what we're
doing it like because part of it is not
that is when people want to do a piece
of it they want me to do a piece of it
right I feel like here's what you should
do no no here's what you should do then
you do that then if you feel called to
that action you do it but the issue is
people with the idea aren't necessarily
the people to do the work including that
person right like that they have the
idea like here's how it would be made
better we need is a group of people who
are committed to doing what calls to
them which means both like finding more
things but call to them and figuring out
you know the pieces my Venn diagram from
from earlier with for any task that
needs to get done
someone needs to know
there's an issue if you aware that the
problems get solved have the ability
knowledge the time everything to be able
to to do it and they have to be active
if they have to want to do it and if you
don't have that all three of those you
have to make compensate so if they don't
want to do it you're gonna need to pay
them so if they want so that they
actually actually do it I'm never gonna
want to they're never you're actually
gonna get in that spot but you'll pay
them to get you no closer okay I'll do
it to it at which degree who's never
going to get a higher level of creation
and doing and all this stuff but of
people then when they're in their spot
when they're in their Center that's what
that Center is it's it's not that
something needs to get done and on
center it's like that's the genius
that's the like where everything is in
flow in society in an individual like
where you know what needs to get done
you can do it needs to get done and you
want to do it you're there and so being
able to okay I have this idea to save
the world who wants to be able to
understand it and then actually
communicate it that'd be great
but I can both reach out and people can
reach out to me and say hey have you
thought about doing this can I do it you
know like I could make a video for you
it's like okay I have ideas on how to
like we could create a crowdfunding
video that go could go viral overnight
and give us ten million dollars to work
with or a million dollars to work with
if it explained a fraction of what was
in my head to people in a way that like
spoke to the masses I'm up to be like
and here's the data behind how we
launched it please save the world
I get that doesn't speak to people's
souls but the emotions and the knowledge
behind that like the that artists get to
create with people that inspire them and
have the tools to do that as well as
people who want to discover and run
experiments are focused in that
direction and just empowered just
empower people to do what they were put
here on this planet to do
and if we unleash a fraction of that
potential we do it we save the poor
Rollo because there's someone out there
who knows how to fix the energy crisis
and someone out there and if there isn't
we get there faster working together
cooperatively we get there faster
together and so I just need to do my
face and explain it but like that's part
of it that's a huge piece of it that we
help each other uncover our genius which
means allowing the places that aren't
genius that are like maybe not up to par
in society accepting that we fall along
a spectrum as human beings everyone like
an infinite number of spectrums like
that
we're masculine to feminine if that is
even a fricking spectrum that it's and
not another hundred dozens of that one
that's my own personal stuff people
relocating to write this I can I will
probably get into that but when we have
the tools to collaborate together when
we have the tools and we design through
cooperation so much efficiency happens
we don't have all of this conflict that
exists in our current marketplace
because we're consumers find from a
corporation who's trying to sell this
stuff and they're trying to get the most
money and we're trying to get the most
value and they're lying to get the most
money we're losing trust because we're
not getting the value and figuring out
like when we lose trust it's not just to
that one it's over and over and over
again we know that we kind of have to
trust branding because it's the best
thing we kind of have to go on but
except for actual information but that's
exhausting and not accessible to a lot
of people so we make that accessible to
a lot of people knowledge is power and
the only way we have knowledge is
collectively together because even if
there's like this inherent inner circle
of people like they're kind of perfect
because like intellectuals who have they
who have whatever like doctors who have
medical information even if you have
that that
Center and they're hoarding that
information like they don't want to have
everyone else have access they don't
have perfect information doctors don't
have they they are like an expert in
that field but an expert in that field
is not better than our collective
knowledge our collective knowledge is
all of that information plus the
information that like patients give you
give feedback in and information on like
understanding the science and
understanding your doctor can't
understand all of the conditions that
are out there for all of their patients
that is an impossible task so they
understand like basic anatomy and and
like they probably don't even understand
so you learned and Chemical Biology like
we would hope that they do some of them
do but not all of them and so their work
they're imperfect individuals working
with imperfect knowledge and together we
can have way more knowledge in health by
working with our doctors like we can
still honor that expertise but giving
them the tools where they're not this
godlike all-knowing beam but doesn't
know isn't a godlike all-knowing being
instead having whatever an expert is in
a medical field in a world that we
co-create together but that doesn't like
we don't look at the medical system and
recreate it all from scratch we can in
like thought experiments together and
see you and have conversations about
what those things are supposed to do and
that sounds awesome I want it I want to
have those conversations and be part of
part of those groups what we can just
like lose our train of thought and
that's that's cool too and it's that
like I'm supposed to be exactly who I am
to put this out in the world which means
my like brilliance and like my non
brilliance and my like all of it because
we have this idea in society that like
there's a specific thing that we need to
be to be professional and to be accepted
by society and that's true to a large
degree and that's where a lot of
privilege comes in is you look at
someone and it's like okay well here's
we we judge them in
a million subconscious ways and
categorize them and any like visions and
people then watching this and then it
like makes me lose my my train of
thought
her over do you have people have
actually live in here you'll have to do
like 20 minute segments not in and if
it's gonna pretty much right about but I
don't think it well I think having a
conversation do a little asking
questions and it is and it's not that
the small it's all it goes like hey
how's it going which drains me and I
don't want to do and more we just like
honor those things and people like why
does everyone need to like how this
constant unlike online communication
drains me ironically don't try to create
it online world like I get that the
forms of communication like typing
thoughts out like it's not the greatest
at it and so it I'm able to lose a lot
of the social anxiety piece of that of
letting it go like oh I didn't say the
right thing just like sense whatever
said said but the other piece of like
the mental work it takes to write
something out even when it's simple is
like I'm just I can't
it's exhausting and like I'm a world to
say that's my excuse for everything but
it's a pretty good excuse like I mean
it's actually true is it okay my house
doesn't get clean it's like we as the
truth is the world that's possible
together he's beyond anyone's wildest
dreams a world there has never been a
time when this planet hasn't known more
like there's never a time of our species
on this planet where we have it no more
and we can actually create that together
it doesn't happen from the hierarchy
down
that's where how we go to war but from
the people who are normally thought like
everyone the people were like everyday
soldiers and the civilians decide we
don't we don't go to war not unless it's
for something huge and then
hopefully we have the tools to deal with
those things right where it's like okay
there's like generations and generations
of trauma here and hatred between these
two groups of people how do we how do we
help them solve it so that's not gonna
continue on for what is the solution and
is there a neutral third party you can
help beside it's like truly neutral and
what does that look like and even those
conversations like does it mean that
that's the same as like the president's
meeting no but people meeting from both
sides and saying like hey here's our
truth and here's our truth and like how
can we find common ground like I want
peace I want peace what is this about
what is this violence where does it come
down to what is the root cause is it an
emotional is it like genetic is like
what is the root cause of this violence
and helping them figure out the story
and how it goes back and how it injured
I don't know I don't know I'm not like I
get that I'm not I'm not equipped to
solve these myself but together we're
truly connected with people around the
planet because we've enabled technology
to be able to communicate in any
language together and it's more about
our personalities or our interest and
whatever else actually draws us to
people you can't villainize the people
that we're interacting with like you you
think it's like oh no my person I have
book club with one of the people in my
book club from is it is like looking in
is in Vietnam and like it's not nope
there it's not a they're humans
like they they're just like us and it's
a very different world to live in when
that's available to you in a real way
like that's we don't we have and let's
honor the history of getting to where we
are in the civil rights movement in all
of these these areas has happened a lot
with um
what's good like there's violence from
the state and from against groups of
people and they they fight back so there
is violence in history and both I'm sure
like both ways but where there's been
the most effect is like with the the
peace movement and I'm now at 20 minutes
and I should go depending on but I enjoy
coming on and talk to you today for 20
minutes and just letting myself ramble
this is what I do by myself in my camera
on like this can never be posted this is
ridiculous you can't post things you
can't edit them you just lose your train
of thought all the time and so although
I do accept a lot my own flow and
rollercoaster of life both of the
motions and ideas and thoughts because
it's what I'm learning I'm supposed to
do I don't know if other people are
supposed to do that but this is magic
and I would suggest trying it and I'm
figuring it out how to communicate that
peace to two people so they have access
to it if it does something that works
for other people maybe it's up maybe
it's uniquely mine but yeah Honorine I
remember them saying so I'm just gonna
go okay
[Music]